They made a homunculus. That is really
my only explanation for what this
research group did. As I'm sure you
know, you can grow all sorts of human
organs just from stem cells like our
friends, the brain organoids. But you
can also connect them to other stuff. We
know that you can take the brain
organoids and then just put them
together and they'll grow together and
think together. They even have brain
waves. And not just delta brain waves
that are associated with an asleep brain
or the brain of somebody in a coma. They
do have stuff like alpha and beta brain
waves, stuff that would be associated
with consciousness, although it's not
really significant, right? Brain
organoids look very much like a preterm
baby. You can see this is what an adult
EEG should look like and that's what a
pre-term baby. So, a baby who's born a
little bit too soon and that's what our
organoids brains look like. But ideally,
they would never really mature into a
fully functional brain because they lack
the machinery for it, i.e. a body. But
what if you give them a body? So, a
research group decided to just put other
kinds of organoids together and create a
little hunculus. They connected a brain
organoid to an eye assemblid. And as you
know, they can have eyes, but they
decided to grow one separately. They
connected it with a motor neuron
spheroid and then a muscle bundle. So
when they shined light on the eye, it
then transferred that information into
the brain which then transferred it into
the muscle body thing and moved the
muscles. They learned to use the
muscles. They essentially treat it like
a body. This is quite bizarre. Not
really the first time that this was
tried. Definitely the first time it was
tried with humans. You can build
xenobots. If you take stem cells from a
frog and then coax it into becoming a
body, it may not actually become a body.
it becomes a xenobot. So, a kind of
muscle fiber thing. But you can give
those muscle fiber things a frog brain
and it'll kind of use the body and move
around. Apparently, the ones with brains
are more intelligent than just the
muscle fiber body things. Now, this
isn't purposeless. Having a little
homunculus like entity is very useful
for medical research. The brains alone
don't tell the entire story. And if you
just have muscle organoids alone, also
doesn't tell the entire story. If you
want to model things like diseases or
medications, it's actually quite
helpful. As for how our brain organoids
are doing in game world, because yes,
you can hook a brain organoid up to a
video game. They've done it with
butterflies. They've done it with Pong.
Researchers have been trying to really
demonstrate that the brain organoids are
smarter than AI models. And that's what
originally was found the first time
someone hooked them up to Pong. That is
also when they claimed they were
sentient. I mean, they kind of are
sentient. You can train them on
dopamine. They don't like disordered
signals. That's how the reinforcement
learning is done. That's how they
operate bodies and game world. They
prefer order, dislike disorder, and can
be reinforced with neurochemicals. And
with that, they learn. They're still
learning better than our best AI models.
Now, 6 years later, they are still
beating AI at Pong. And it kind of makes
sense. That's what these guys are
evolved for, right? They are tiny human
brains or little analoges to human
brains grown from our own stem cells.
They're supposed to be learning how to
interact with an environment. It makes
sense that they would do better than AI
because we're kind of trying to make
something analogous to intelligence
versus just harvesting intelligence. And
of course, you can hook them up to AI.
They've been used for learning things
like speech. They can recognize human
speech. They're not super great at
putting out the kind of linear
information that we like AI to do, but
they're better at doing things like
operating a body that AI just kind of
sucks at. One of the issues that
researchers have with these guys is
communicating with them. This is where a
lot of neuromorphic robotics comes in
handy. When you have a sensation, it's
immediately turned into a nerve impulse.
For computers, it has a few steps in
between. Graphine has been really useful
for taking stimuli immediately turning
it into an electrical impulse and that
can communicate with the brain organoids
which is what these guys did here. They
also brought back the need for organoid
eyes which I find fascinating. If you
want to learn more about this stuff let
me know. I largely feel like people have
gotten bored of it, but it's so weird.